<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brume</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic website of Tomoya Takano（高野智也）</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 10:32:47 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 10:32:47 +0900</lastBuildDate>

    
      <item>
        <title>New grant starts</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/new_grants</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The JSPS funds the 3 years &lt;a href=&quot;https://kaken.nii.ac.jp/en/grant/KAKENHI-PROJECT-22K14110/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; on the passive noise based high temporal monitoring of the fluid pressure changes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Move to Hirosaki University</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/move_to_hirosaki</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I moved to Hiorsaki University (Graduate School of Science and Technology) as an assistant professor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Move to ERI, the University of Tokyo</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/graduation</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished my PhD in Geophysics at Tohoku University and moved to ERI (University of Tokyo) from April 2019 as a Research Fellow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lapse-time dependence of dv/v in response to tides</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/array-izuoshima</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Takano, T., T. Nishimura, H. Nakahara, E. Fujita, and H. Ueda (2019), Sensitivity of seismic velocity changes to the tidal strain at different lapse-times: Data analyses of a small seismic array at Izu-Oshima volcano, J. Geophys. Res. Solid Earth, 124, https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JB016235. &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/Takano+2019.pdf&quot;&gt;[PDF]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We investigate seismic velocity changes in response to the tidal strain at Izu-Oshima volcano, Japan, by analyzing the data of permanent seismic stations and a small seismic array to evaluate the characteristics of strain sensitivity of velocity changes. We estimate the seismic velocity changes by phase differences between cross-correlations functions of ambient noises at the frequency of 2-4 Hz stacked for time periods with different tidal strain amplitudes. The seismic velocity changes decrease and increase during dilatation and contraction periods, respectively, when analyzing the cross-correlations functions at early lapse-times ranging from 2 to 7 s. However, we find that strain sensitivity of the seismic velocity changes decreases when analyzing the cross-correlation functions at later lapse-times from 7 to 35 s. Applying an array analysis to the cross-correlation functions, we observe apparent velocities of about 1 km/s at the early lapse-times and those of higher than 1 km/s at the late lapse-times. Since the group velocity of Rayleigh waves is 1.1 km/s at Izu-Oshima volcano, the apparent velocities at the late lapse-times may indicate the scattered or reflected body waves incident from a deeper region. Decrease of strain sensitivity with the lapse times therefore results from the emergence of body waves on the late lapse-times. These results highlight the need to pay attention to wave types of cross correlation functions and their paths to interpret seismic velocity changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>a moth that looks like a brown leaf</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/bug</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I found a moth that looks like a brown leaf in front of my appartment in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/photo/Moth1.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Photo1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/photo/Moth2.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Photo2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>EGU・dv/v in response to different direction of tidal strain</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/egu2018</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the EGU General Assembly 2018, I presented a work on characteristics of strain sensitivity of seismic velocity changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular I talked about the seismic velocity changes in response to different direction of tidal strain by using ambient noise recorded at active volcanoes in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2018/EGU2018-12501.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Visiting student at ISTerre (Grenoble University)</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/grenoble</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I stayed at ISTerre in Grenoble university from 2018/4/1-2018/10/3. I worked on velocity changes of ballistic waves by using Large N arrays on Piton de la Fournaise with Prof. Florent Brenguier and Prof. Michel Campillo.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AGU・dvv/v caused by the tidal strain at Izu-Oshima</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/agu2017</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the AGU Fall Meeting 2017, I presented a work on characteristics of strain sensitivity of seismic velocity changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked about the seismic velocity changes in response to tidal strains at different lapse-times. In the presentation, I discussed the observed velocity changes with the wave properties of Green’s function by applying an array analysis to cross-correlation functions of ambient noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://agu.confex.com/agu/fm17/meetingapp.cgi/Paper/270586&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSJ・dvv/v caused by the tidal strain at Izu-Oshima</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/ssj2017</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the SSJ Meeting 2017 in Kagoshima, I presented a work on characteristics of strain sensitivity of seismic velocity changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>VSJ・velocity changes caused by tidal strain using a small array.</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/vsj</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>Tomoya Takano</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the VSJ Meeting 2017 in Kumamoto, I presented a work on characteristics of strain sensitivity of seismic velocity changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    

  </channel>
</rss>
